A Guide to the Records of J.M. Hardy & Son of Staunton, Virginia 1871-1922
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Records of J.M. Hardy & Son of Staunton, Virginia 1871-1922
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11254
There are 80 items, 1871-1922.
There are 80 items pertaining to the business of J.M. Hardy & Son of Staunton, Virginia, including advertisment brochures, business papers, and repair books.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This material was purchased by the Library from High Ridge Books, Inc. of Rye, New York, on August 30, 1996.
Scope and Content Information
There are 80 items, 1871-1922, pertaining to the business of J. M. Hardy & Son of Staunton, Virginia, a firm that sold and repaired wagons, carriages, and similar vehicles together with the parts and equipment needed for them. There are two advertisement brochures, 1890, for the Columbus Buggy Company of Columbus, Ohio and for the H. H. Babcock Company's "Happy Thought Wagons," sold by J. M. Hardy & Son. Among the business papers are accounts with carriage and wagon manufacturers, saddlery companies, and others, a few Augusta County receipts, and miscellaneous items. The majority of the collection consists of repair books for the paint shop and for the trimming, paint and smith shops of J. M. Hardy & Son.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subject.
Contents List
- Advertisement Brochures for Buggies and Wagons 1890 (Box 1)
- Bank Books 1873-1874 (Box 1)
- Business Papers 1871-1912 (Box 1)
- Name Plate for the "Happy Thought Wagon" n.d. (Box 1)
- Notes and Bills Receivable/Payable 1881-1894, 3 volumes (Box 1)
- Paint Shop Repair Book 1898-1900, 4 volumes (Box 1)
- Paint Shop Repair Book 1900-1909, 5 volumes (Box 2)
- Smith and Trimming Shops Repair Book 1897-1898 (Box 2)
- Trimming, Paint and Smith Shops Repair Book 1902-1909, 5 volumes (Box 2)
- Trimming, Paint and Smith Shops Repair Book 1910-1912, 3 volumes (Box 3)
- Trimming, Paint and Smith Shops Repair Book 1921-1922 (Box 3)
- Repair Order Book (blank) n.d. (Box 3)